Ibrahim Youssef

[Frontend developer - React - Vue - Next]

Date of Birth: 13/12/1995 | **Nationality**: Egyptian | **Place of redience**: Cairo

Phone: tel:01147359396

GitHub: https://github.com/Ibrahemyoussef2020

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ibrahim-youssef-2a65b1261/

Gmail: mailto:lbrahimYoussef.dev.

Summary

Ahighly motivated andskilled Front-End WebDeveloperwithexperience in HTML,CSS,andJavaScript. Proficient in responsive design and able to create visually appealing and user-friendly websites. Strong problem-solving skills and a passion for staying up-to-date with the latest web development technologies.

Academic Qualifications

Bachelor of Computer science – Alazher University: Grade: Very good | Duration: October 2013 – May 2017

Experience

Front-End Developer - AiTech, 6th of October City (Full-time): Duration: Aug 2024 - Present

Front-End Developer – People and institutions (Freelancer): Duration: Jan 2021 – Aug 2024

Projects

Drosat – Using Vue: It is a platform that provides online private education in which students participate with teachers, the students' level is evaluated, exams are given to them through AI services, and the results are sent to parents.

Link: https://drosat.com/

Germany-CRM - Using Vue: It's the new professional website

t o Ai Tech company

Link: https://aitech.net.au/

Kuttab – Using Vue : It is a platform for memorizing the Holy Qur'an, displaying recitations, and following up on teachers' accounts

Link: https://kuttab.online/

Amazon – Using React :It is an imitation of Amazon with all its features, but it is uploaded to the JSON server, so it takes time to download, and work is underway to add Express - Mongo to it.

Link: https://amazon-clone-frontend-frwHYPERLINK "https://amazon-clone-frontend-frw6.onrender.com

Stamena gym - Using React : It is a fully gym application sell and subscribe and follw and buy within it but for reson have been rebuilt with json server without backend

Link: https://dashboard-gym-frontend.onrender.com/

Tawasal – Using NextJs: it's the frist step for building an arabein social media app But it is under preparation now

Link: https://twasal.vercel.app/

Brand ecommerce – Using NextTs: it's a fully ecommerce like amazon but different design and features and The next version is being made in mongodb to solve the problem of slow data coming from the json server { in error case refresh until mongo being ready}

Link: https://brand-ecommerce-tau.vercel.app/

Skills

- Soft Skills:
 - Quick learner for new technologies
 - Strong communication and presentation skills
- Technical Skills:
 - Javascript including (JaQuery, Typescript) Vue, React, Next, Redux
 - **React** including (Next, Redux, React-query)

- **Vue** including (Option apis, Composition apis)
- Css including (Sass, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Mui)
- Html

Certifications

freeCodeCamp—(2023) - JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

freeCodeCamp—(2023) - Responsive WebDesign

InturnGrow—(2024) - React challenges